Matteo Bertrone

SOFTWARE ENGINEER . RESEARCH ASSISTANT AT POLYTECHNIC OF TURIN

24, Corso Duca degli Abruzzi, Turin, Italy 10129

🛘 (+39) 334 798-6923 | 🗷 m.bertrone@gmail.com | 🎢 mbertrone.github.io | 🖸 mbertrone | 🛅 bertrone

"Everyone thinks of changing the world, but no one thinks of changing himself" - Leo Tolstoy



Summary_

I'm research assistant at Department of control and computer engineering of Polytechnic of Turin, Italy, where I developed Polycube, an open source framework to provide fast, in-kernel, virtualized network functions. I love to code, but I also love to share ideas and feedback with my team, not only technical ones.

I'm working on network programmability, SDN and could computing, eXpress Data Path (XDP) and eBPF. I deal with distributed programming, APIs design, concurrency, and performance optimization. I spent some time visiting and collaborating with tech companies in Silicon Valley, as part of my research work.

Work Experience

Polytechnic of Turin

Turin, Italy

RESEARCH FELLOW & SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2017 - PRESENT

- Core developer of Polycube: I am part of design and development process of the framework from the very beginning.
- Implemented virtual network services (bridge, router, nat, loadbalancer), without kernel modifications requirements.
- Managed to create a clone of iptables firewall, exploiting efficient algorithms and XDP optimizations, leading up to 10x performance gain.
- Developed a networking provider for OpenStack (iovisor-ovn). Increased visibility by publishing it under iovisor community.

Huawei Technologies

Santa Clara, CA, U.S.A.

INTERN

May. 2018 - Jun. 2018

• Development of Polycube framework and services, as collaboration with Polytechnic of Turin.

may. 2010 3an. 201

Nebbiolo Technologies, INC. (Start-up company)

Milpitas, CA, U.S.A. Feb. 2017 - May. 2017

CONSULTANT

• Design and deploy of a lightweight bridging networking solution, as a substitute of Linux bridge.

Santa Clara. CA. U.S.A.

PLUMgrid INC. (Acquired by VMware)

NTERN

• Developed networking modules, that can be interconnected to provide networking for OpenStack.

· Overcome eBPF language limitations, and achieved an efficient solution without modifying Linux kernel.

Sep. 2016 - Jan. 2017

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

EiSWORLD

Mar. 2014 - May. 2014

Turin, Italy

• Developed a network analysis and diagnostic tool for Fiat Chrysler Automobiles, used to debug and detect issues on dealers network.

Projects & Open Source_____

PolyCube

github.com/polycube-network

POLYCUBE IS AN OPEN SOURCE FRAMEWORK TO BUILD VIRTUAL NETWORK FUNCTIONS WITH XDP AND EBPF

Jan. 2017 - PRESENT

- I'm core developer of Polycube, major contribution to design and implement the framework.
- Implemented an abstraction layer to easily deploy services (e.g. bridges, routers), configure them, create virtual topologies, and connect them
 to Dockers, namespaces, VMs, NICs. Developed a rich set of services, e.g. bridge, router, load balancer, nat, DDoS mitigator.
- Designed and developed a bpf-based clone of iptables, using Polycube framework. Presented at Netdev 0x12 (Montreal, Canada July 2018)

Iovisor-OVN

github.com/iovisor/iovisor-ovn

Sep. 2016 - Jan. 2017

IOVISOR-OVN PROVIDES AN EFFICIENT DATA PLANE REPLACEMENT FOR OPENSTACK NETWORKING.

- Developed and designed as part of my master thesis, and during the internship in PLUMgrid.
- Presented at Open vSwitch 2016 Fall Conference (San Jose, CA, U.S.A.)

Skills

Programming C/C++, eBPF, Go, C#, JAVA, LaTeX

Tools Linux, Git
Languages Italian, English

Education.

Polytechnic of Turin

Turin, Italy

MASTER'S DEGREE, COMPUTER ENGINEERING, 110/110

2014 - 2016

Polytechnic of Turin

Turin, Italy 2011 - 2014

BSC Degree, Computer Engineering, 110/110

January 6, 2019 Matteo Bertrone · Résumé